Jake deVarennes

☑ devarennesjacob@gmail.com ♀ Houston, TX 🖈 jakedevarennes.com 🔘 jakedevar in jakedevar

₽ PROFILE

Software Engineer with two years of experience in both Ruby and JavaScript ecosystems. Led architecture design with a team of four to build Constellation, a geo-distributed load-testing framework capable of handling up to 10,000 virtual users.

EXPERIENCE

Software Engineer, Co-creator, Constellation □

2022 - Present

Constellation is an open-source tool that provides a simple command line interface for deploying geodistributed load testing on all 26 AWS-hosted regions.

- Researched existing products to find the most impactful features and explored architectural challenges
- Spearheaded development of the data-aggregator component to handle a capacity of over 130 requests per second using Node.js and AWS SDK
- · Constructed a data visualizer which provided a comprehensive way to ingest data returned from the load generation test from all 26 AWS regions
- Developed CLI command capable of executing in a single command what would have originally taken over 7 API calls to AWS to accomplish
- Created a buffer system for the data-aggregator component, which decreased data loss to 0% at a rate of over 130 Rps
- Wrote code from scratch which replaced the functionality of 3 open-source tools, reducing the overall API complexity
- Engineered data ingestion and retrieval system optimized for high read volume and complex analytical queries over large datasets
- Collaborated with a remote team of engineers from the US, New Zealand & Canada, across four time zones involving daily stand-ups and pair programming

Software Engineer, Self-employed ☑

2021 - 2022

Developed open-source web applications with technologies such as Node, Ruby, Rails, PostgreSQL, React, JavaScript, HTML, and CSS.

- Bin of Requests: A Node.js application built using Express, MongoDB, Postman, and PostgreSQL to capture and monitor HTTP requests
- JobQuery: A job keyword tracking software that processes 900 job listings at once and analyzes the top keywords present in each listing; built with Node.js, Express, MongoDB, Puppeteer, and React/Redux
- Swillreno.com: Constructed website using Wordpress for local business within a very sensitive time frame

Sales Associate. Ford Motors

2019 - 2021

- Sold new and used vehicles in one of the toughest markets this century
- Mentored junior salespersons to significantly improve the onboarding experience

® SKILLS

Languages (JavaScript/Node.js, Typescript, Ruby, Go, PostgreSQL, CSS, HTML)

Cloud (AWS, DynamoDB, Lambda, EC2, API Gateway, S3, Timestream, Digital Ocean, Fargate, DynamoDB)

Libraries & Frameworks (React, Redux, jQuery, Express, Jest, Handlebars, Puppeteer, MaterialUI, Bootstrap)

Other (Docker, Git, GitHub, Neovim, Linux, RESTful APIs, PostgreSQL, SQLite3, MongoDB, Nginx)

EDUCATION

University of Nevada Reno, BA General Studies

2014 - 2018

Software Engineering, Launch School

2021 - 2022